Awesome
weekend. It truly was. Um, just I I just
want to start by uh, you know, really
congratulating the city and the people
in this city for uh, for the draft here
and how it turned out. I I can't tell
you guys how awesome the feedback has
been uh, from the people that I talked
to uh, and all the excitement down
there. I mean, from
uh you know, politicians, the people uh
obviously I can't tell you guys what Art
Rooney and Dan Rooney did for this. Uh
it's just it was it's it's just it was
been great to see. Um everybody from the
league office, you know, the
commissioner and his staff and it it's
just I I can't tell you how, again, I
keep using that word awesome. It's just
it was awesome. It truly it it truly has
been. And you know, and it concluded
with that excitement with Eli. I mean, I
wasn't expecting to see that on TV. and
you can't help but get emotional when
you saw that at the end. But truly truly
truly a uh tremendous weekend for the
city of Pittsburgh and you know for the
Steelers and I think for the NFL. It
it's hopefully we get it back here
again. It was enjoyed every minute of
it. Um you know be before I take any
questions I wanted to thank uh you know
my personnel staff. Uh I got to tell you
guys in my opin I my my staff's second
to none. They're they're I'm so proud of
these guys and you know they work so
hard and u for me and for the
organization and they they do a
tremendous job and um
you know when um we we have such a good
process. I I truly love our process and
um you know we had a great board and you
know when you when you uh have a good
process and you know you trust your
board like we do and you know sometimes
the draft throws curve balls your way
and um you know things just sort of sort
out uh from there when that happens you
know if you have that trust and I can't
say enough about those guys and they're
you know I just can't do this without
them and they're awesome and also want
to thank uh Mike and his coaches man the
these guys. You know, the the time and
effort they put into this. You know, we
haven't done this in what, 19 years with
the new staff here and the way these
guys uh just work so hard. Man, I can't
thank you guys, coach, for for this
process. I know it's hard moving to
Pittsburgh and lots of stuff going on
personally and, you know, getting stuff
ready from the football side and then
you got me throwing a lot of stuff your
way. Um, so appreciate all the efforts
uh uh from the coaching staff, too. you
know, everyone else in the organization,
I said, they we have a great
organization here, great people, and um
really really pleased with how things
turned out. Um you know, we drafted what
do we end up with? Uh 10 picks and you
know, I'm not going to talk about each
one of them individually right now. If
you guys I'm sure you guys will fire up
some questions, but um like I said, that
ending was tremendous, too. I mean, I'm
sure you guys all saw it. That was that
was pretty cool to watch. So, from
there, happy to take any questions.
Omar, was the um offensive heavy draft
was that kind of reflective of having
Mike in his background? What what you
want to do on offense or Sure.
>> No. Uh he uh you know, it just sort of
came that way. You know, that's how the
draft the draft uh uh sort itself out
and you know, it just you know, we
didn't go in there saying, "Hey, we're
going to draft nine offensive guys and
one defensive guys." You know, we like
like I mentioned, we you know, you trust
your board, you trust the process, and
it all sorts out. And that's just sort
of how they how it turned out. talking
about that first round pick. Um, we
haven't talked to you since obviously
the reports came out with you guys being
on the phone with Mai. Can you kind of
take us through the you mentioned the
curveball this draft price just take us
through the moments that kind of ensued
uh after that? Yeah, you know, when when
you're the draft happens, there's a lot
of excitement that goes on to in and um
you know, there was no ill intent and
you know, made the call, but um as I
mentioned, when you have a a good
process and you trust your board and you
know, the draft throws curve balls at
you and and every round, trust me, it
happens throughout the throughout the
draft and some public, some not. And um
you know, things just sort of take care
of themselves. after taking a swing at a
receiver there initially at 21, how do
you feel you guys pivoted to address
that position? And Mike, how do you feel
your room is now after batting the guys
that you did today?
>> Well, I think Omar's really has answered
the question. Um, you have to trust your
board. I've always looked at the draft
board similar, you know, to calling a a
huge game, you know, but obviously with
a lot more energy in it. I mean, there's
so much time and energy goes into
putting that board together and it's
this draft this weekend was very
refreshing when you see need hit value.
When value hits need and so when you
when you get down to those picks, you
know, you're usually talking about two,
three, four players and um but it really
did it, you know, we did not go into the
draft saying we're going to take so many
offensive players or so many defensive
players. we wanted to raise the level,
you know, of our of our talent and we're
we're aware of positions that we would
probably want to add to, but um you
know, and that's the case with receiver.
I mean, it's just I mean, he was he was
right there and um that's that's a great
pick pick right there.
>> Did you Bernard and um the kick returner
from Iowa feel?
>> We got what
>> how did you feel about the room after
you got Bernard in the second round?
>> Yeah, I mean we we feel you know
obviously we traded up to get Jeremy.
So, uh, I think that kind of speaks for
how we feel about him. Um, you know, we
think he's going to add to the room. And
then Kaden, you know, that's that's on
coach. He's going to have some fun with
him, I think. And, uh, you know,
obviously his his, uh, he's going to
help us in the return game, which was a
area need for us.
>> Adding, uh, Drew Aller in the third
round, what kind of value do you feel
like you got with him and what are you
getting and that made him the attractive
pick?
>> I mean, it's about the quarterback room.
Uh, I've always approached it that way.
I I learned it that way as a as a young
coach. Um it's it's about training the
whole room together and we you know we
had an opportunity to get on the field
last week uh for two days, you know,
with Mason and and Will and and now we
had Drew. So this this is this is this
is the goal. This is the outlook. I
mean, we talked about it in my interview
just from a philosophical standpoint. So
we we want to have a healthy, you know,
quarterback room that that we're always
developing. We're always developing it.
It's the most important position maybe
in sports. I mean, it's very difficult.
There's a lot that goes into that. Uh we
have a way of how the quarterback will
be trained here. Uh I've done it a long
time and um it's great to have two
really young guys that I'm I'm extremely
excited about.
>> Does drafting Drew affect what you guys
expect to hear from Aaron or what you
want to hear from Aaron?
>> It was it's No, not at all. This is uh
this is about developing the room and
trying to make the room as deep, you
know, as we possibly can.
>> If you if you do get an answer from
Aaron who does decide to come here,
would you be comfortable with two guys
who haven't taken a snap in the NFL as
backups or would you need to to keep
Mason to give yourselves another guy?
>> I mean, these are all questions,
answers, hypotheticals that really it
won't change what I've already said. I
will I will coach the hell out of that
room. Um, I have a lot of confidence. I
have history and experience that that
um, you know, I will give everything I I
can to any quarterback in that room. So,
we we we want to grow the quarterback
room. We we don't want to, you know,
just rely on one quarterback.
>> AFC North in terms of the size, the arm
strength, the hands. Is he the AFC North
quarterback we've been talking about for
a while now?
>> Well, I I think the biggest thing is you
recognize where you play. I mean, you
you know, you're going to have eight
home games. So, u it's no different with
the return game. You know, the return
game is is was a very important, you
know, outlook uh for for Omar and I from
the first day we start talking about the
draft.
>> What did it be like by Drew Waller? And
um was he the guy you wanted on day two?
>> Definitely. I mean, uh I I think like
anything, you know, I I believe in first
impressions. you know, I've had a chance
to to have, you know, watch him play,
but meet meet him at the combine. Um,
and really all the quarterbacks that
came into the meeting room there did
very well. But I I just, you know, I
liked everything about him. I think he's
I think he's young. I think he's got a
lot of great, you know, a lot of room
for growth and and, you know, he's a
young man that can throw the ball with
the best of them and that that that's a
great starting point to have. Mike, one
of the challenges in having two young
quarterbacks and giving them time to be
able to develop.
>> CBA rules is the only challenge we have,
but um you know, everybody coaches under
him, but it's it's a good place to be.
Um you know, I was very impressed with
Will last week. You know, I knew he was
a good athlete. Um you know, we had a
chance Tom and I had a chance to break
down. We do a thing called quarterback
profile. So, we had the chance to
videotape that on Tuesday and and that's
something we'll share, you know, with
Mason and and Will on Monday. But, you
know, it's there's a training regimen
that's involved. Um, but, you know,
we'll stick to it and um I'm I'm excited
about both those guys.
>> How about roster rules too, Omar? Like
you'd said, Mike, on Monday, you'd like
to have four and use the practice squad
the right way. How what are the
minations that you can kind of use to
your advantage to try to hold on to four
>> four quarterbacks
>> practice squad? Like how do you how do
you do that?
>> Yeah. I mean those are all you talking
about once we get into the season.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean those are all options. You
know the one thing about this league is
you know there's natural attrition that
happens uh once you get into training
camp and injuries happen and that sort
of sorts itself out. But you know the
league's set up where you have uh
options and opportunities to keep your
best players.
>> Mike, have you ever had a service
academy guy and Hiden specifically? How
do you envision
>> I'm sorry I didn't hear the first part
of that.
>> Have you ever had a service academy guy
and how do you envision Hiden being
used? Oh, I I think the biggest thing is
um you know, obviously have a lot of
respect for for what what he's done the
last four years. Um we we talk a lot
about how many downs a player plays. You
know, does he play all four downs? You
know, his ability to play multiple
positions. So, I think Eli definitely
brings that to the table. So, um I think
both, you know, we I just I met with uh
Angelico briefly, you know, earlier. So,
I I think we're going to open up our
playbook a little bit. Mark mentioned
the emotion that came with drafting Eli
and you know the crowd going crazy for
you. What is that moment like to draft a
Pittsburgh native guy and see him get to
walk across the stage in front of this
Pittsburgh crowd?
>> Oh, I mean I I think everybody in the
room felt it. I felt it. Um I I couldn't
imagine what it would you know what it
been to walk out there like that. So
just really proud of him and you know
and I think the biggest thing for me as
a coach is to create opportunities for
for all these guys and especially for
Eli. more bigger picture just um when
you enter the draft with 12 draft picks
that's a lot of capital. What was your
plan to try to leverage that to your
advantage and how do you feel like you
executed it?
>> Um I think the execution went um went
pretty good. You know, really really
happy with how with the players that we
acquired. Um you know, we went into I
mentioned to you guys, I didn't know if
we were going to end up with 10 or 14
picks. You know, we were open to
anything. There was some good players in
the draft. It there really was. And uh
you know, we got 10 good ones. And um
you know, I'd like to tell you that I
went in there saying, "Hey, we're going
to end up with 10 or end up with nine or
eight and four first rounders, but you
know, you just sort of have to let it
come come to you and uh you trust your
process."
>> When you talk to player like Kaden whose
contributions have primarily come on
special teams, how do you try to balance
the value that that provides compared to
maybe a depth at another position or a
guy who could be a potential future
starter in
>> Yeah, I mean I think his resume speaks
for itself, you know. Um he's very
productive in that area in college. I
mean that's that's I mean just just look
at his stats. I mean I think that speaks
for itself. But you know it was a neat
position. Um he was the top guy in that
area in my opinion. Um and uh you know
for us that's the value we we we put on
him and we we feel really good about
where we got him.
>> Max is it a case where since he took up
football so late do you see a higher
ceiling that there's still ascension in
terms of where his game can be or he
learns more even?
>> Oh absolutely. Absolutely. I mean, he
he's so impressive. I mean, you guys got
to meet him got to meet him uh yesterday
and uh I mean, there's there's a lot to
like there and a lot of growth to come
and you know, I'm excited for him being
a Pittsburgh Steeler for years and years
to come.
>> I know Mike was giving you grief about
it, but how did the 8minute clock thing
come into play and was was that at all
an issue with the whole thing with Mai?
Were you like did you have time to go
back to the Cowboys and say,
>> "Hey, you know, can we get can we can we
swing something here?" Yeah, it was it
was a non-issue. I probably made more
out of it than I I I should have the
other day, but it it was fine.
>> You first impressions earlier. What were
your first impressions of Jennings
Dunkerk? He's a seems like a pretty
interesting guy and uh would stand out
even in a crowd of 10 offensive linemen,
I think, when you look at him.
>> Yeah, I mean, we love his hair. I mean,
we're we're it's, you know, I'm sure our
marketing marketing department likes it
even more, but no, he's impressive. Uh I
know James Camp and and and the whole
offensive line staff. I mean just you
know so impressed with him and I think
it's just like anything when you you sit
there and watch these men whether you do
a zoom or meet him in person you go
through the you know the process first
time you you may meet him is at the
combine but he's you know when he walked
through the door I mean he's he's a very
very impressive young man.
>> What stood out to you guys about Gabriel
Rubio?
>> Sorry.
>> What stood out to you guys about Gabriel
Rubio?
>> Well I just think number one you watch
the way he plays and you look at you
look at his skill set. I mean, he's he's
a he's a Pittsburgh Steeler defensive
lineman. I think he's an outstanding fit
for the 34 and I thought that was a
no-brainer pick right there.
>> Why is fullback still important in your
offense and when your thoughts on Riley?
>> Well, Rally, I think when you look at
Rally, his versatility just jumps off
the charts. I mean, if you go back
through his background at Wisconsin, you
know, he played in the two back offense,
played in the three surface offense
where he played, you know, both the
fullback up on the line, did all the
movement ability. You know, he played
one year in a in a run and shoot type
one back. So, he has some he has some
one back running ability, too. And and I
cannot, you know, tell you how impressed
I was with him and his story uh to leave
Wisconsin and to go to Indiana and be a
captain on the national championship
team. So, um, this is an outstanding
pick and and on top of that, I know I'm
excited about it cuz I I love the two
back offense. There's a lot of things
that, um, you know, you you start in
this league in the '9s where, you know,
two back offense was a primary component
of normal down in distance. Now, to be
able to bring some of that back, it's
something that did a little bit in
Dallas, you know, down there to, you
know, 23 and 24. So, to be able to have
that, but the big part of it, no one's
happier than Danny Crossman. I mean, you
know, he's a fourcore special tamer. You
know, he'll have a chance to potentially
be a leader captain type on special
teams. So, uh, I thought that was an
excellent pick there by Omar.
>> Mike, on the offensive line, you have a
lot of youth, a lot of positional
flexibility, and then also the question
mark's health. How you go about sorting
out where all these moving pieces fit
together?
>> Great question. Uh, there's different
ways of doing it. You know, I've done
left side, I've done right side. I think
you got to look at the experience of
these guys, how we bring these rookies
into the into the into the place. So,
um, those discussions have started. Um,
and frankly, until we sit down with the
players, you know, I'm not going to sit
here and talk about it openly until
then. But yes, it's I mean, because you
you want to create an opportunity for
everybody to have a chance to line up.
But, boy, the longer I do this, it takes
it takes the whole group to get through
get through the season. So how we train
them together in their in their position
flex will be will be a big part of our
decisions on how we start.
>> Omar, you ended up drafting a lot of
guys that were younger but also had
multi-year experience. Was that kind of
a concentrated effort to get guys that
had multiple years of starting but also
I think were 23 or younger. I think the
only guy that's 23 or older was Oian out
of your picks.
>> Yeah. You know what it's goes back to
you just kind of trust your board. We
didn't go into it saying, you know, we
want to average this age group by the
end of the or this amount of experience.
It just it just sort of and we trusted
our board and it came to us that way.
>> I appreciate your question cuz I I
didn't realize that.
>> Yeah. Until
>> you said it. Yeah.
>> It's good homework.
>> Two more two more guys. When you get to
that stage, you got 200 lb guy that runs
a 43. Is that something that you just
look at the that skill set in terms of
the safety you talk the first the first
time around pick?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> That that size, size, and speed.
>> Yeah. size and speed, you know, value at
that at that spot. Our scouts really
liked him. Um, just, you know, special
teams contributor. Um, a lot to like
there.
>> Is Eli is Eli a running back who catches
the ball or is he more of a receiver?
How what's how do you use him? You said
to open the playbook,
>> definitely no position flex. I mean I
mean he can play from the slot, he can
play from the back field. You know, you
see him out displaced. Uh, you know, I
think anything when you you put a young
man in the receiver room, he has to play
all three positions. that's the way we
want to play. That's the way it's been
introduced the last couple weeks. Uh but
his ability also to play from the back
field and you know just you know the
diversity is is is important. So like I
said um you can't do everything Randle
Cobb you know I've had different players
in the past. So we'll definitely look at
those things.
>> All right. Hey guys, I I meant to
mention one thing when I in my intro. Um
she's gonna not be happy with it, but
Moren Manion, you know, our assistant,
she's she's retiring and uh she's been
here since uh my first day in 2001 and
she's very special to all of us down
there and you know, I just, you know,
she's probably not be happy with what I
said this guys, but I just want to
publicly say, you know, how much we're
going to miss her and appreciate uh all
her all of her her hard work through the
years. She's been a a great asset for us
and uh we're going to miss her. So, if
you guys get a chance to see her, if I
know some of you guys know her, just
please congratulate her. So,
>> all right. Thank you.
>> She's she's a manion. I played for her
uncle, so she's right stuff.